the scripture
and you pay a high price for it and we
have the best illustration is as Arizona
yeah
Arizona Institute to make some money and
they will never for level the year they
introduced the lottery the copper went
bad
and the state had another million
dollars
[Music]
true 100 million dollars
sometimes it never happened in the
history of Arizona so
from the time they started the lottery
they have been poor and they had deficit
they have to have reason with employment
and cut down and budget and I worked for
the state and I don't want this
happening
on the
God does it in such a way that now the
officials responsible for the lottery
say we have a hundred million dollar
deficit can you imagine who must do the
plane without the lottery
[Music]
so they they never understand they are
not supposed to
but it is a fact
Breath of Life that Arizona is poor
because of the loss and just got off
this stuff
and the same is true with us if we are
to Bear God's law and gamble in order to
make money will probably make ten
thousand and then lose 100.
somewhere else
it's the way that works when he breaks
his bar
you have a blind form
Ula so they sweepstakes and appliances
they keep sending the nails is that the
same thing exactly the same thing now if
they send them say you already won
something
you didn't get it and they say
they send it to him
yeah because you have not invested in
anything exactly you didn't go after you
didn't apply for it you didn't
participate in it
but it came to you
right
however I don't think
God wants to send you money or send it
to legitimately it doesn't happen
you know each one of us by the ways have
a number of dollars assigned to him or
to her there's no way you're going to
get any money there's no we're going to
get any less you cannot escape from it
it's a little bit off the subject but
related
my sister didn't know
sent my wife last week
a big package
in a lot of people it's a gift
and my wife
experience
pick up the
wallpaper and I was going to crush them
and put it in the garbage can or rather
than whatever it is yeah
then I saw that all the storms
on the
coverage
about five dollars
so there are many possibilities
[Laughter]
I personally took it as Mana from Heaven
either one possibility
I go I cut the thing
and I could go to the Post Office ask my
son to drive me who is going to Costa
two three dollars and say Mr postmaster
new people for God to do it would you
please actually or I give it to someone
the most problem yourself will get it or
I returned it to my sister-in-law
instead of using for next year when you
give us another
okay oh
I use it for
mainly
for a Scotland right I would say I put
it in my stamp collection
from Islamic point of view which do you
think this is something happened last
week
made a mistake
what do you think
I would consider a gift from God because
the first law of this
I don't know they went beyond the reason
of the limits and they're integration
you know you look at the impression of
the possible and there's lessons of
in the country it was an average 10
percent in the last 10 years but the
postal office went up like 100 percent
so from that point of view I disagree
with the post office and I was
considering forget from God I would take
the stamps
but they came to me
[Music]
it looks like that it is
something to write money
from a person
uh that's making money
somebody was really shipping
but at the same time
two years ago you were sending the
classes package for less than a pound a
pound or less for 23 cents
that was a 63 cents
yeah so that's 300 percent
it's a hundred percent per year and
that's way out of proportion so
you're Justified when God sent you
somehow unconscious steps in my opinion
to justify the music
and it's usually a very violent
well I think in my if you go to me
myself
but this happened last week
several times
you use it again because otherwise it's
gonna be that story
in the country
they're all back to you intoxicants from
Germany
okay
right in the world
does not say why because they don't
understand
a lot of people want to see uh
that
destroys the method
s
[Laughter]
there's also a
statement about the charity in the same
version
so it tells us how much how much charity
we can give of our own you know
money or whatever position we have and
God said the excess the ones the fortune
that we do not need for uh
right
foreign
[Music]
we have to raise them up as Muslims
lucky
these two verses are very clear
and God God shows his Mercy again says
here he's coming he said I could have
made a very more harder commandment for
you but he saw a merciful he mentioned
he makes everything easy for us
foreign
very very bad
the person who is taking care of the
ocean is very important and he
also affect the weight for instance for
administering the money of the ocean
and as a service today
do you expect to enter a paradise
without undergoing the same thing
has lost before you
they suffered hardship and adversity
So Sick Enough that the messenger
they suffer the hardship and adversity
they were so safe enough that the
messenger and those who believed with
him said
where is God's Victory indeed God's
Victory is always near
Okay so
the idea here is to
worship God Alone no matter WhatsApp
but all circumstances it's a matter of
knowledge
you you can see the conclusion that God
is one and he's the only Master he's the
only one that benefits your heart
is the only one who controls the mind
and hearts of the people around you
he makes him love you or hate you or
care about you or don't care
and with this knowledge it doesn't
matter what happens
adversity or happiness is
it's a fix
definitely
and you know that it doesn't matter what
happens so
also we are here
for the test
and God wants to be proud of you and
want to show you off to the engines and
say look at my service
he or she worships me no matter what
happens
without ever seeing it and this is the
whole idea of our existence
and the end of the verse says indeed
God's Victory is always near
it must be noted also here that after
the test today
there is a final test
after the final test that is absolutely
there's nothing but kingship on Earth
as God promises when you come to the
conclusion the divorce of God Alone
and it takes a long time the road is
long and hard
it's a continuous struggle
but there will come a time when you are
perfect worshiper of God Alone
then there is no hardship
and you would can see this in Surah 24
these are some of the verses that we
must remember all the time page 243
the great cross
because God promises those respectifies
page 243.
God promises those among you who believe
in World righteousness that they will
make them Kings on Earth as he did for
those before them and that he would
establish for them they are related but
it shows for them and that he would
substitute Security in place of their
fears all this because they worship me
alone without idolizing anything besides
me
if anyone just believes after this that
these are the women
come and sit next to that
Saint John said next tomorrow
see this this promise is true now do you
remember Joe
had lots of parts of adversity
but uh
once he passed the test
he recovered his head recovered he
recovered his payment and even twice as
much
he recovered his voice and twice as much
so he was under the test for as long as
he needed to be tested to prove himself
through all the best
also you must think of adversity as a
cleansing and policy process
when you join the awareness of God I
don't want to expect some Prophet at the
beginning
because you're cleansing all the masked
sins all the past errors
and this can be cleansed only by praying
for them in this world
so all the adversity that you have at
the beginning to come to come join this
mask you're going to have five or ten
years of adversity
because it's a polishing process
polishing you know how polishing goes
detect a piece of Rock
and polishing machine very noisy
shipping off pieces
but then what comes out is a beautiful
gym
and that's what what will come out of
that after you go through the policy
process
polishing is not easy
so what I'm saying is that there is a
find at first
verse 3 and 4.
the first is horrified
for the day
it's 401. 8.
verse two this one verse two at the end
of it
says whoever observes righteousness
towards God he will create and exit for
him
an exit of every problem
and provide for him when he never
expects
When You observe God
the sacrifice a job or
a source of income
directly for the sake of God he would
provide for you what you never expect
for the best of the day
401.
the end of books too
this is the best I wanted to remember
whoever observes righteousness towards
God he will create an exit for him and
provide for him once he never expects
anyone who trusts in God God will
surprise him
God always carries out his decisions
you have come to the conclusion that God
is the king the absolute ruler of the
universe
and you'll carry out this promises and
this decision
you just you just have to believe it you
must have absolute confidence in it
tomorrow there is a mandatory law
insurance law
and we have
quite a few of us have decided that we
have insurance for God but if you are
with that
you have the best insurance
and you just have to believe that
nothing would happen to you when it
happens to the rest of God this this is
the difference between the insurance
companies and God's insurance
we don't have anything happen to you
your caught your head
with the insurance companies will have
the accidents and the insurance company
will pay for you
you have the agony of the insurance of
the accident
and the inconvenience of losing the car
from you
for having an operation
and the companies will pay
but you just have to have the confidence
that when you have insurance with God
nothing will happen to you
also you must know that if God wants to
get you and get you whether you have
insurance or not
God says they cannot escape from me
that's what they said deserve the pins
for a little accident
what it isn't sickness
you can't get away from my insurance
company yes
yeah when you have to then you have to
we will not
buy insurance unless we have to but but
it appears that God is already taking
care of us
because the law enforcement to put the
prosecutors are all protesting the law
and they are making an official
foreign
so I called the civil liberties Union
myself and I told them this country
that's our religious beliefs and they
didn't do anything about it
so we will not buy insurance until we
have to
because the Quran says if you have to
eat pork or drink wine or do anything if
you have to without being malicious of
the liver
then you're not committing yourself
the book I'm saying is What God Says and
provide for you who else you never
expect you must you must know that
you must have that confidence
if you have the slightest doubt it will
not work
and this insurance business we we're
gonna
to finance for a long time
when we had that conversion to the
extent I told you about our friend tarek
when the guy says look as soon as
insurance
well and he said I have a trust of God
so what's his phone number
it wasn't taken I mean it was the
natural question coming afterwards but
then of course
because he had a person on his hand on
the paper he says write the whole number
with a tune-up place
somebody
so uh
got all those cursed out his decisions
he's the absolute
he runs this country
or any government anywhere God runs
everything
you go to the end of verse 4.
just whoever observes righteousness
towards that God will make everything
easy for him
everything will go easy for you
you will not suffer any function
there's absolutely no humidation for the
Servants of God
you go apply for a job and you will be
the boss because your soul takes over
the place
and you'll see them
running to serve you
they may not be Elijah
see
whoever observes righteousness towards
God God will make everything easy for
him
this is God's promise as documented here
in his private message
so we'll go back now to page 23.
about hardship as a mandatory test
over and over we see people who are
immensely Wealthy on the TV and they're
complaining about unhappiness how
unhappy they are
foreign
[Music]
earthquakes
hurricanes floods all these are uh
punishments
punishments and tests because all these
things are absolutely controlled by God
there is a statement that I will answer
your question
since Surah I believe 64. let's look at
this beautiful
so 64 plus or minus two sure so I'm
gonna find it for you
yeah 11 verse 11.
there's no disaster so it's accepted
accordance with God's will
[Music]
this is this is the law
no disaster strikes accepted accordance
with God's will
no no pain no disaster nothing happens
except by personal decree from God
because it is not simple
it's not it's not easy to
so that's a painful headache for example
it has to be a personal degree from God
outside
your question Diana yeah
everything in this world is miserable
every piece of ice that Philip Denver
gave up miserable fight
it was measured yeah
everything is planned
every the minutest details very
carefully planned come to the left
nothing is coincidental or haphazard
nothing as individuals as Nations as a
world
just think every drop of water is
measured exactly where it goes
where it's gonna fall how many inches
from an ant that's crawling moves around
that's right
thank you
okay
recipients of charity
they ask you about Charities say
Charities shall go to the parents the
relatives the orphans the poor and the
aliens any righteous work you do God is
fully aware thereof
fighting may be forced upon you though
you dislike it
but you may dislike something which is
actually good for you and you may like
something which is actually bad for you
God knows why you do not know
they ask you about the desecration of
the Sacred months by fighting therein
say fighting during the sacred months is
sacrilege but repelling the people from
the path of God and disbelieving in him
and in the sacredness of the Sacred
mosque and evicting the people there
from are all worse sacrilegious in the
sight of God
oppression is worse than murder
they will continue to fight you until
they revert you from your religion if
they could
those who revert from the religion and
die as disbelievers have wasted their
Works in this life and in the Hereafter
they have deserved hell wherein they
abide forever
as for those who believe immigrate and
strive in the cause of God they have
deserved God's mercy God Is Forgiven
merciful
so it's two different subjects here
the 215 talks about the charity
and it tells us specifically that
the charity first goes to those that are
closest to us to those that were most
responsible for our parents and our
relatives
and then next are those that
that really need economic help or don't
have someone else to rely on the orphans
and the poor and then the alien
and so this is a carefully uh
that we are given the details of how
terrific
they don't need it
in other words each text curve is all
and here's what takes care of his own
there will be no misery in the world
if the relatives are rich
then you find orphans
children children who have no parents
one or two girls
and then any Court you put and then they
added so in this world
see any righteous work to do God is
fully aware of it and it seems that
charity is more than just economic help
it can do any kind of help
any
righteousness
doing what is right in this world what
other people feel for simply politeness
or
anything we try to do to make the
the world better
treat the other peoples
it's a merciful towards
people around us
then God is
is because
we want to express God's mercy
we want to
we desire God's forgiveness and God's
mercy and these qualities
in by showing our appreciation the
desired form we express toward the world
around us
[Music]
foreign
which I take to mean
basically in a war type of situation
though it may be
well when we think about it we think of
taking up Arms Of Violence rather than
simply argumentative so another level it
could be
simply not giving in to it
to any kind of
oppressions
Maybe
economically political or social but no
I you know
the only there's only one reason in
Quran for fighting
it has to do with the freedom to worship
God Alone
that's it
it's absolutely no other reason
for fighting only if it's gonna
interfere with your freedom of
practicing The Logical pleasure
and oppression meaning trying to impose
any new religious view on you or to
prevent you from practicing your
religion
there is one reason for fighting
a fighting might be imposed upon you let
somebody come to say don't pray
foreign
if your country gets into war with
another country and you're required to
go and fight
your drafted or anything
that's the cause of God the only
fighting is
so whatever whatever they're
unforeseeable reasons or circumstances
fighting for land or because of
importance or in because of countries
all the
rest of life because God did not to yet
use both of them
if we had Jesus and passport
everything you're forced to defend
yourself when somebody else wants to
drive you away from your your own land
you have to fight's awesome
defense
it isn't because of God
I mean if they the what it says about
evicting you from your houses or you
evict them from where they Addicted to
You
know if they're simply fighting not
they're not perceiving religious reasons
[Music]
did we did we go through the rules of
warrior because that is
yeah yeah we did yeah
that Wars are only Justified
all those multi-defense
those throughout the world they say do
not fight them at the sacred mosque
unless they attack you there
foreign
and his
is one rare person who comes before he
would Leary of the Hadith business so he
can see us just because we believe in
the Quran at all but anyway I hope I
want to tell you is that people try to
defense the sign I think
and and twice but they felt missile
every time
so there are invisible costs around us
here we don't need to do anything this
Edge
is an edge of mental
let them debate
rather than
The Sword and fighting
anyway you can't fight because the plant
or the land
unless you're attacked
adorning is something and
right into something else
but they don't bite
it's a means of supporting your
to earn the honestly
if you if you would join anything and
you simply earn a living for something
if it's part of an institution that's
involved in sometimes
yeah
you don't want to earn your living
setting liquor for example breaking
God's law I suppose you went towards
asking about joining the Armed Forces or
to joining the armed forces and there's
no war it's just like any job
I suppose your government gets into war
with another country that's when you
have to make a decision I wonder this is
because of God or not
because of God
well I suppose uh you're working for a
big company and they're producing
something that you know like
or say nepalm or chemical weather
you know maybe you're not directly
involved in the manufacturing but are
you a protesters there's no wall
perfectly all right because
we prepare the maximum power that you
have
water
aggression is
me
so joining the Armed Forces or making
weapons or
anything that is not war
I look at this wall then you have to
make a decision if it isn't because so
it's okay to have a nuclear on the way
that's right
we didn't have a local weapons of this
country it can be used
in a way
[Music]
prepare the maximum power you can
possible
let us here
so I want to go to the index yeah I I
meant to talk to you about this once
before because we said trust in God and
don't make any weapons
free empty strike which is attacking
first
they call it pre-empty strikes
away it's a matter of strategy
Surah 9 verse 41.
you can really be mobilize
Surah 8 verse 16.
this is a commandment you share
124.
60 you shall prepare for them all the
force and the equipment you can hostel
in order to deter the enemies of God and
your enemies as well as others you are
not aware of
why God knows them
anything you expended the cause of God
would be repaired to you without belief
in Justice
it's a very respectful Commandments to
prepare
you must you must always have a
deterring
thoughts
so it is you trust in God but you follow
what he says
there wasn't any battle in which the
Muslims were a great round number oh
yeah and there was a sense
[Music]
from the Strategic point of view the
logistic point of view the the numbers
of heat soil and they try to analyze it
militarily and this doesn't make sense
the Muslims defeated to this believer
but
also the Battle of your book when they
hit and when they did something they
never outnumbered and in the battle of
the person because the best house in the
world
Rockets
oppression is worse than murder
it's
it's an attempt to manipulate somebody's
mind
and
to
make other people follow one's own
material desires
whoever is a depression
just that
they're trying to change your mind
but to make you revert
to a situation of unbelief in other
words the Muslims now have come
they have arrived at the truth all right
and for you to go from truth bad to
unbelief that is
the murder of the song so it's not a
matter of just changing your belief but
it's going back to unbelief which is
terrible the Quran says many times once
you have to believe many people will try
to let you revert to angry so that is a
it's terrible because the the punishment
for
the punishment for unbelief after belief
is greater than just Anthony from
beginning to end
I think Quran says that too
it says it in the next
um
is disbelievers have wasted their Works
in this life
they have deserved hell and they are
there forever
those who believe
immigrate and strive in the cause of God
so it's time I think that if we are
oppressed then we can't fight him it's
better to get up and leave and go
someplace
we can
follower faith God
commands
to write I guess it's telling us to
fight if we can if not to try to get
away from that situation
foreign
God is forgiver and merciful
yeah this is a very interesting verse
because people have pointed out many
times I think they
interpret this verse out of context how
can operational prosecution be worse
than the market they say but actually
you read the whole thing
I think what it means is this in the
long run going to hell
for six words the demander nothing
offensive